他们说胜者书写历史
They say that history is written by the victors.
而保护伞公司的历史
This then is the history of the Umbrella Corporation.
就是由科学家詹姆士·马尔库斯教授所执笔
Formed by a crusading scientist, Professor James Marcus.
马尔库斯有个年幼的女儿叫艾丽西亚
Marcus had a young daughter, Alicia.
她患有早衰症  这种致命疾病会逐渐消耗人的体力
Afflicted with "Progeria". A progressive fatal wasting disease.
早衰即过早衰老  等艾丽西亚25岁的时候
Progerie caused premature aging. By the time she was 25,
她的身体会老得和90岁老人一样
Alicia would have the body of a 90 year old.
马尔库斯竭尽全力去救她 但希望渺茫
Marcus was driven to save her but the odds seemed impossible.
在疯狂制造药剂的同时 艾丽西亚的父亲还会记录她的日常
Even as he worked desperately to create a cure, the young girl's father would record his daughter;
她的声音 她的样貌  欲使她永生
Her voice, her likeness. Saving her from posterity.
但之后便取得了突破
But then the breakthrough came.
马尔库斯发现了T病毒
Marcus discovered the T-Virus.
注射入体内 它会侦测并修复体内受损细胞
Once injected, it would detect and repair damaged cells within the body.
这就是个奇迹
It was a miracle.
艾丽西亚·马尔库斯得救了
The life of Alicia Marcus was saved.
T病毒得到广泛应用
The T-Virus had a myriad of applications.
被用于上千种不同的疾病
Treating a thousand different diseases.
人们仿佛在一夜间迎来了新的纪元
Overnight, it seemed a new era was dawning.
对于感染 病痛 或是衰老再没了惧怕
A world without the fear of infection, sickness or decay.
但事实并非如此
But it was not to be...
T病毒有着一些不可预见的副作用
But the T-Virus has a certain unforseen side effects.
先生 先生  快过来
Sir, sir! Over here.
他快没呼吸了
He's not breathing.
第一个不死之人诞生了
The first of the undead was born.
此次事故被迅速掩盖
The incident was quickly covered up.
事情尚未完全平息 詹姆士·马尔库斯却和他的商业合伙伴亚历山大·艾萨克斯博士激烈地争吵起来
In the aftermath, James Marcus argued furiously with his business partner, Dr. Alexander Isaacs.
我不在乎会付出多少代价  我们必须终止该项目
I don't care how much it costs. We have to close the program down.
詹姆士 我们会身败名裂的
James, we're gonna be ruined.
我已下定决心
My mind is made up.
躺回床上去 艾丽西亚  我和你爹在聊天呢
Off to bed Alicia. Your father and I are just talking.
快去
Go on.
艾萨克斯教授便成了他合作伙伴遗孤及其半个公司的监护人
Dr. Isaacs became the guardian of his dead partner's child and her half of the company.
因高尚情怀而建的公司 如今已堕落为贪婪与权欲的信徒
The corporation that had begun with such lofty ideals had been seduced completely by greed and power.
为了控制保护伞公司带来的巨大利益
To help him control the now vast interests of the Umbrella Corporation,
艾萨克斯博士编了一套强大的人工智能程序
Dr. Isaacs created a powerful artificial intelligence.
艾萨克斯将电脑的交互界面做成艾丽西亚·马尔库斯的样子
Isaacs used the likeness of Alicia Marcus for the computer's interface.
并称这台电脑为红后
Isaacs called the computer, the Red Queen.
十年前 浣熊市发生了泄露  T病毒从蜂巢的地下实验室泄露了出去
Then ten years ago, in Raccoon City, there was an outbreak. The T-Virus escaped from an underground laboratory called the Hive.
美国政府试图通过投放炸弹来阻止这次泄露
The American government attempted to contain the outbreak by detonatng bomb.
炸弹炸毁了浣熊市
It devastated Raccoon City.
却没能阻止空气传播的病毒
But it couldn't stop the airborne infection.
病毒泄露 没到几天就在世界范围内传播开来
The viral outbreak spread across the world within days.
人类对此束手无策
Human kind was brought to its knees.
最终 肩负最后及最大希望的人们决心在华盛顿特区背水一战
Finally, the last and best hope of humanity gathered and took a last stand in Washington DC.
但我们并未认识到我们已经深陷囵圄
But we didn't realized that what we had walked into was a trap.
我是爱丽丝 这是我的故事
My name is Alice and this is my story.
也是我故事的终结
The end of my story.
你好
Hello.
有人活着吗
Is there anyone alive in here?
你好
Hello?
你是来幸灾乐祸的吗
You come here to gloat?
我的卫星显示在地球表面有4472名人类存活
My satellite show, there are 4,472 humans remaining in the surface of the earth.
他们会在接下来的48小时内死亡
They will cease to exist in under 48 hours.
你想从我这得到什么
What do you want from me?
想让我说你赢了吗  你灭亡了人类
Do you want me to say that you've won? You've wiped out humanity.
不 恰恰相反  我想让你阻止我
No, quite the opposite. I want you to stop me.
小心身后
Behind you.
身手不错
Nicely done.
我不相信你
I don't trust you.
介于我们之间的恩怨  你信我才怪呢
Given our history, I'd be surprised if you did.
但是你若不干涉 这次病毒爆发将无法阻止
But unless you intervene, this flowtill will be complete.
届时将无人幸免
There will be no survivors.
我怎么才能帮助他们
How can I possibly help them?
保护伞公司开发了气态病毒抗体
Umbrella developed an airborne anti virus.
如果传播出去将会消灭T病毒以及任何感染T病毒的生物
If released it would destroy the T-Virus and anything it has infected on contact.
- 那就能终结这一切？  - 准确的说 是的
- all this could end?  - precisely
哪能找到这种病毒抗体？
where is this anti-virus?
就保存在浣熊市地下的蜂巢
Beneath the streets of Raccoon City, in the Hive.
你为什么要帮我
Why would you help me?
我的编程不允许我毁掉保护伞公司
My programming will not allow me to harm the Umbrella Corporation.
但你不受约束
But you are bound by no set of constraints.
你要与保护伞公司为敌  与制造你的人为敌吗 为什么
You'd turn against Umbrella? Against the people who created you? Why?
在48小时内赶到浣熊市的蜂巢  你自会找到答案
Get to Raccoon City in 48 hours. Make it to the Hive. And then you'll have your answer.
你说的话 我一个字都不信
I have no reason to believe a word you say.
的确  但我有你特别想要的东西
True. But I can offer you something you want very much.
什么
What is that?
向威斯克复仇
Revenge. Wesker.
他将你引至华盛顿  假装使你恢复力量
He led you all here to Washington. He pretended he gave you your powers back.
然后再背叛你
And then, he betrayed you.
他现身在何处
Where is he?
他就在蜂巢
He just landed at the Hive.
我正在重设你的手表
I'm resetting your watch.
倒计时开始
The clock is ticking.
爱丽丝 我们十年前在蜂巢的失败导致了现今的一切 就当是赎罪吧
Alice, 10 years ago in the Hive. We both failed. We let this happen. Make it right.
你们就这点能耐吗
Is that all you got?
爱丽丝
Alice.
十年前在蜂巢
10 years ago in the Hive.
将不会有幸存者
There will be no survivors.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
我在哪儿
Where am I?
说话啊
answer me
你们怎么回事
What's wrong with you?
安静
Be quiet.
这是谁干的
Who did this?
我说了 安静
Quiet. I told you.
闭嘴
Silence.
最终你还是醒了
So you're awake at last.
我曾手刃了你
I killed you.
但我还活着
Yet here I am.
克隆体  我杀的是你的克隆体
A clone. I killed your clone.
你和你的克隆体们
You'd be most troublesome to me.
真是我的大麻烦呢
You and your sisters.
现在我终于捉到了你
Now I have you.
清除你们的任务早该在一年多以前就完成了 但是你拖累了我们
The cleansing operation should have finished over a year ago, but you slowed us down.
以至于我不得不自控
So much so that I was obliged to take command of myself.
你能够终结这一切  为什么不这么做
You could end all of this. Why haven't you?
有意思
interesting
有人给你透露了点实情 是吧
Someone told you something, didn't they?
别急 很快你就会上赶着来告诉我的
Ah well, you'll be begging to tell me soon enough.
她没有信仰  我们该怎么处置没有信仰的人
She's an unbeliever. What do we do with unbelievers?
扔出去
Cast her out!
扔出去 扔出去
Cast her out! Cast her out! Cast her out!
动手
Come on!
扔出去 扔出去
Cast her out! Cast her out! Cast her out!
上帝借洪水之力来扫荡地球
The Lord created a flood to cleanse the earth.
下了40天日夜不休的大雨  相比我们的方法耗时略长 但效果相同
40 days and 40 nights of rain. Our method is taken a little longer but the result will be the same.
我们即将迎来的是一个正直且纯净的世界
A world ready for the righteous and the pure to inherit.
再过12个多小时 我们就会抵达浣熊市
We reach Raccoon City in just over 12 hours.
这么久 我担心你体力跟不上呢
I doubt even you can run for that long.
告诉我你知道的一切
I want to know what you know.
她挺不住的时候再喊我
Tell me when she's ready to talk.
威斯克
Wesker.
艾萨克斯博士
Dr. Isaacs.
看看我在路边找到了什么
Look what I found on the roadside.
看来你华盛顿任务并没有那么成功嘛
It would appear your mission to Washington was less successful that you made head.
- 不可能  - 希望你没留下其他祸根
- impossible  - I hope you didn't leave any other loose ends.
还有件事
There's something else.
我觉得她知道了以空气为载体的病毒抗体
I think she knows about the airborne anti virus.
怎么可能
How can that be?
目前我还不清楚  但我们在去浣熊市的路上抓到了她
I don't know...yet.  But we caught her on the road to Raccoon City.
她去那儿还能为了什么
Why else should she be headed there?
把蜂巢的安保等级调到最高  不允许任何人进出  爱丽丝打算开口的时候我会跟你说的
Raise the security level of the Hive to maximum. No one in or out. I'll let you know when she talks.
上帝与你同在
God go with you.
你也听到了  把安保等级调到最高
You heard him. Security level to maximum.
遵命
As you wish.
你们去上面看看
Get up there and check it out.
放了我
Release me.
打开舱门
Open them.
好的 好的
Alright, alright.
你没有骑这辆摩托车的权限 看你往哪逃
You can't use it. You can't escape.
卧槽
Oh Jesus.
先生 她逃了
Sir, she's gone.
目标离我们72英里 正朝我们逼近
Target is 72 miles and closing.
封锁整个蜂巢
Lock down the Hive.
准备好防御措施
Prepare defensive measures.
并且提醒我们在浣熊市的操作员
And alert our operative in Raccoon City.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
空气传播的病毒抗体
Airborne anti virus.
48小时
Under  48 hours.
赶到蜂巢
Make it to the Hive.
放开他  赶紧放开他
Let him go! Let him go now!
- 道客我早就跟你说了 - 冷静 克里斯汀 - 我早说过你是错的
- I told you Doc - calm down Christian  - I told you you were wrong.
冷静点
Calm down.
我们刚有机会的时候就应该把她杀了
We should've killed her when we had the chance.
还是把武器放下吧 不然她会开枪杀了我们俩
Put it down please before she tries to shoot the both of us.
这里面是什么
What's in this?
纯肾上腺素  我需要你醒过来
Pure adrenaline. I needed you awake.
为什么
Why?
在你来的方向 有什么东西过来了  一个很庞大的东西
There's something coming. In the same direction you came. Something big.
放开他  放下武器
Let him go! Put it down now!
爱丽丝
Alice?
保护伞公司在阿卡迪亚抓住了我
Umbrella captured me at the Arcadia.
他们把我带去了一个叫蜂巢的地方 后来我们摆脱了防守 杀了飞行员 然后飞机坠到这了
We were headed somewhere called the Hive. Got loose, killed the pilot. Crashed here.
道客和其他人把我从废墟中拖了出来  我的命是他们给的
Doc and the others pulled me from the crash. I owe them my life.
道客  看东部方向 有东西朝这来
Doc! There to the east, still headed our way.
你知道那是什么吗
You know what it is?
保护伞公司的艾萨克斯博士
Umbrella. Dr. Isaacs.
我以为你杀了他
I thought that you killed him.
我也那么以为
I thought so too.
要不了几个小时 他和他的丧尸军团就能到这了
He has an army of undead with him. He'll be here within hours.
我们怎么办
What do we do?
我们特么为什么要问她
Why the hell are we asking her?
她就是一个陌生人  我们不应该信她
She's a stranger. We shouldn't trust her.
道客 你他妈别碰我
Don't you touch me Doc.
放下武器
Put it down.
你放下武器
You put it down.
老兄 听我说 你觉得自己应该是总指挥不代表你就是总指挥
Hey, look at me. Cause you think you should be in charge doesn't make it so.
道客 听着  你们会后悔的  你们所有人都会后悔的
You listen to me Doc. You're gonna regret it. All of you. All of you!
我得赶去蜂巢  你必须带着大家离开这
I have to get to the Hive. You have to get this people out of here.
这里有小孩 伤者还有老人  他们在开阔的马路上哪有生存的可能
There are children, injured, the elderly. Now what chance they have in the open road?
总比他们在这活下去的几率大
Better than they have here.
这座建筑很安全
This building is secure.
对丧尸而言这可能很安全 但艾萨克有装甲车 火箭筒  还有其他能瞬间撕裂这栋建筑的重量级武器
Maybe from the undead but Isaacs have armored vehicles, rocket launchers, heavy ordinance that can tear this place wide open.
道客
Doc!
她到底怎么了
So what happened to her?
她碰到我们在角落设的陷阱了  本来这些陷阱是为了防丧尸的
she was open one of the traps, made out of . They are intended for the undead.
这是什么
What is this?
我们这的特色  每个人都喝过
Speciality on the house. everyone feed it on time.
我凭什么信任你
Why should I trust you?
给
Here.
道客  你得出去看看  大家都很害怕 而且克里斯汀在帮倒忙
Doc? You need to get out there. People are scared and Christian is not helping.
你得让大家知道发生了什么
You need to let people know what's happening.
那好  我得走了  对了 你的朋友不会有事的
Okay. I gotta go. Hey, your friend's gonna be okay.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你知道吗 我和他
You know he and I...
我注意到了
I noticed.
蜂巢里到底有什么
So what's in the Hive?
保护伞公司研发出了解药  一种空气传播的病毒抗体
Umbrella developed a cure. An airborne anti virus.
它能杀死所有T病毒的宿主
It'll destroy anything infected with the 6-Virus on contact.
谁告诉你的
Who told you this?
红后
The Red Queen.
你居然相信她
And you believed her?
万一我们真的能结束这场灾难呢
What if we could end all this?
那你怎么办  他们给你也注射了T病毒
What about you? They infected you with the T-Virus.
你打算散布的这种反病毒会杀死你
You release this anti virus, its going kill you.
破釜沉舟 义无反顾
Whatever it takes
爱丽丝 我不
Alice, I'm not...
你知道我是对的
You know I'm right.
好吧
All right.
我们先击败艾萨克斯  救完这些人 我们再一起去蜂巢
We stop Issacs here. We save these people and we go together.
我们时间不多了  开始吧
We don't have long. Let's get to it.
你们还有什么其他的防御武器吗
What else do you have for defense?
我们没有特别多的枪支 但我们有很充足的汽油供应
Not too many firearms but we have a big supply of gasoline.
给 你需要一件武器
Here, you need a weapon.
我们现在都给她枪了
We're giving her a gun now?
克里斯汀 别激动
Take it easy Christian.
老兄 你愿意卸下你的警戒心 可我不愿意
You can let your guard down if you want man, I don't intend to.
我骑着摩托刚到这的时候 有个人一直在盯着我
When I rode in here, someone was watching me.
他本来能开一枪提醒我你们设下的陷阱 但他没开枪
It could have called out to fire to shot to warn me about the trap but it didn't.
什么意思
what are you saying?
当心有人背后捅刀子
Watch your back.
艾萨克斯博士 看样子她又成功逃脱了 而且他们很多人还活着
So Dr. Isaacs, seems you let her slip through your fingers. A lot remains of them.
可别忘了你是在和谁说话 她在哪
don't forget who you're talking to. Where is she?
浣熊市的安置区  有线人汇报说她正为一场战斗做准备
The settlements in Raccoon City. Our informant reports that she's preparing for a fight.
很好 我一个小时后就会到那
Good, I'll be there in an hour.
就是这样  继续推
That's it. Keep moving.
我们需要所有的汽油桶  放在那
Need all the gasoline cans. Over there.
克莱尔说是你建的这个
Claire said you built this.
是的 没错
Yeah, that's right.
这原来是一台窗户清洗机  我改装了一下
This used to be a window washer. I made a couple of changes.
你从哪学来的
Where did you learn to do that?
我爸原来经营一家汽车拆修厂  我很讨厌那  谁知道呢  大概当时还是有在认真看吧
My father used to run a chop shop. I hated it. Who knew? I guess I was paying attention after all.
很好 因为我还想让你再继续改装一下
Good, because I'm gonna need you to make a few more changes to this thing.
准备好武器  填好高爆弹药  不准留下活口
Ready the weapons. High explosive rounds. No survivors.
他来了
He's here.
他们来了  快关上大门
They're coming. Close the gate!
我的老天  这简直是一个军队
My god! It's an army.
我们该怎么办
What are we gonna do?
是啊 我们该怎么办
Yeah, what are we gonna do?
我们要杀光他们所有人
We're gonna kill every last one of them.
准备开火
Prepare to fire.
大家准备好
Get ready!
点火
Lighten  up!
开炮
Fire!
我草他妈
Damn her.
再次填装
Reload.
全面停止进攻
Close it up. Full stop.
把诱饵放出去
Release the bait.
那有一位幸存者  打开大门
There's a survivor. Open the gate.
打开大门
Open the gate!
开火
Open fire!
给她打掩护
Keep them off her.
准备第二发
Mark ready 2.
开炮
Fire!
克莱尔 道客  快去那把她带进来
Claire, Doc! Get out there, bring her in.
加把劲
Come on.
等等
Wait.
她快到了
She's almost there.
开火
Fire.
该死
Damn you.
关门现在
Close the gate now.
克莱尔 它们已经突破大门了
Claire, they've breached the gate.
克莱尔
Claire!
开火
Fire.
瑞瑟尔 现在
Razor, now!
好 你们听见她说什么了  推
Right, you heard her. Push!
从大门撤退  撤回到路障那里
Abandon the gate. Pull back to the barricades.
看起来她好像没上钩
Looks like she's out of tricks.
向顶上射击
Target the roof.
所有人趴下
Everybody get down!
趴下
Down!
爱丽丝 我们到达路障了
Alice, we're at the barricades.
克莱尔 你们得把它们阻止在那里
Claire, you have to hold them there.
道客小心
Doc!
爱丽丝 我们撑不住了
Alice, we can't hold on much longer.
现在撤退
Get out of there now.
补给火力  现在
Back up! Now!
全力向她射击
Bring all guns to her.
开火
Fire.
她在哪
Where is she?
她去哪了
where did she go?
找到她
Find her.
关闭通风口
Close the vents now!
别开枪
Don't shoot.
你很快但你还不够聪明
You're fast but you're not too smart.
求你别开枪
Don't shoot please.
他在哪
Where is he?
那边
That way.
节约点子弹
Save your ammo.
这里丧尸太多了
There's too many of these things out there.
我来处理
I'll take care of it.
前进
Move out!
走吧
Let's go.
敬请享受你的旅程吧
Enjoy the ride.
伙计们
Guys.
你说
Go.
有些东西你们得来看看
There's something here you gotta see.
还有两波丧尸冲我们来了 地平线那里一波
Two more armies of undead headed straight for us, there on the horizon.
另一波从那过来的
The second over there.
我们用来防御的汽油已经用光了
We're out of gasoline for defenses.
我们必须赶到蜂巢 这是我们唯一的机会
We have to make it to the Hive. It's our only chance now.
我和你一起去
I'm coming with you.
算我一个
Count me in.
我也去
Me too.
还有我
And me.
所以我之前误会你了
So I was wrong about you.
你哪里也不能去
There's no way you're going.
我们知道前方危机四伏 我们想加入进来  拜托了
We know the pit, we wanna come. Please.
带上些工具 你们会用上的
Grab some gear, you're gonna need it.
那里
There.
那是什么
What is it?
一部分被爆炸暴露的蜂巢  这儿就是我们的入口
Part of the Hive that was exposed by the blast. That's our way in.
行动
Let's move.
我来领队
I'll take point.
启动安全监测
Activate security measures now.
蜂巢安保系统已完全启动并自动操作
Hive security fully activated and automated.
不
No.
解除自动操作  我要亲自操作防御系统
Disengage automation. I'll handle the defenses myself.
我来控制防御系统的话将更有效率
The defenses would be more efficient if I retain the control of them.
是么
Really?
我好像记得她上次活着离开了这里呢
I seemed to remember last time she was here she walked out alive.
同样的错误我不想犯第二次
I don't intend to make that same mistake.
如你所愿  蜂巢防御系统由你全权掌控
As you wish. Hive defenses are now in your hands.
放出地狱犬
Unleash the Cerberus.
地狱犬准备完毕
Cerberus are in play.
这一切爆发之前 你是一个人吗
You have someone before all this?
有没有丈夫  家庭
Husband? Family?
不记得了
Can't remember.
怎么可能
How's that possible?
我醒来的时候一切已经开始了
I woke up just when all this was starting.
之前的事情不怎么记得了  有时候我感觉这就是生活的全部 亡命天涯 大开杀戒
Can't recall much before that. Sometimes I feel like this has been my whole life,running, killing.
那是什么
What is it?
有东西在跟着我们
Something stalking us.
- 你确定吗 - 我就是干这行的
- Are you sure? - This is what I do.
快  快跑
Run. Run fast!
跟上
Come on!
所有人都还好吗
Is everyone okay?
走这边
It's this way.
就在我们后面
Right behind us.
它们为什么停下了
Why'd they stop?
- 也许它们害怕了 - 害怕什么
- Maybe they're scared.- Scared of what?
下面肯定有什么东西让它们害怕
Whatever's down there.
封锁蜂巢
Seal the Hive.
我们走
Let's go.
爱丽丝
Alice!
你还好吗
You okay?
我的弹夹已经用完一半了
My mag's half empty.
我把枪丢在湖那里了
Lost my guns at the lake.
我只剩下枪膛里的子弹
I only have one round left.
和一个备用弹匣了
One spare mag and I'm out.
没有枪 没有弹药  我们在这儿到底怎么办
No guns, no ammo. What the hell are we gonna do down here?
爱丽丝 那束光是怎么回事
Alice? What's with the lights?
这个区域被毁了  电力不稳定
This part of the Hive is damaged. The powers erratic.
这个 拿着
Here, take this.
听着
Hey, look.
你之前问我为什么与保护伞公司反目 我承诺要告诉你答案
You asked why I would turned against Umbrella and I promised you an answer.
T病毒爆发过后不久 一份机密文件传到了我的数据库里
Soon after the T-Virus was released, a secret file was uploaded to my data stream.
那是病毒爆发17个月以前 一份保护伞公司高层会议的视频记录
It was a recording of a meeting of the Umbrella high command. Dated 17 months before the viral outbreak occurred.
我们今天坐在一起 讨论的不只是公司的前景 还有人类的宿命
We're here today, not just to talk about the future of this company. We're here to talk about this destiny.
世界的终结
We're here to talk about the end of the world.
我们站在末日的边缘 经历着无法治愈的疾病
We stand on the brink of Armageddon. Diseases for which we have no cure.
原教主义自求毁灭 对于核武器我们又束手无策
Fundamentalist stage who called for our destruction. Nuclear powers over which we have no control.
即便我们度过这一切难关 还是会有其他不可避免的威胁
And even if we navigate these dangerous waters, we face other even more inevitable threats.
全球变暖将在80年内融化两极的冰盖 淹没地球上百分之90可居住的区域
Global warming will melt the polarized caps within 80 years, flooding 90 percent of all habitable areas on earth.
要不了50年 食物产量就会无法供养疯狂增长的人口 饥荒和战争无可避免
Unchecked population growth will overtake food production in less than 50 years leading to famine and war.
这不是猜想 而是事实  殊途同归 我们的世界终将毁灭
This is not conjecture, this is fact. One way or another, our world is coming to an end.
问题是 我们会随之灭绝吗
Now the question is...will we end with it?
你有什么好的建议吗
What do you propose?
我建议我们按照自己的方式亲手毁灭这个世界
I propose that we end the world but on our terms.
一场精心策划的世界末日
An orchestrated apocalypse.
清除地球上的人口 但完整保留其基础设施和能源
One that will cleanse the earth of its population but leave its infrastructure and resources intact.
这一想法已经成功实施过
It's been done once before with great success.
被选中的少数人将在安全的地下平安度过这场灾难 而不是创世纪里所说的诺亚方舟上
The chosen few will ride out the storm not in an ark as in the book of Genesis but in safety underground.
末日结束后 我们将在一个净化过的地球上重建属于我们的辉煌
And when it's over, we will emerge unto a cleansed earth. One that we can then reboot in our image.
你要怎么做到这一切呢
And just how do you intend to achieve this?
救世之法就在我们手中
The means of our salvation are already at hand.
我为你们带来了 T病毒
I give to you...the T-Virus.
他们是故意泄露它的
They release it deliberately.
这视频传进我数据库的时候 让我的编程出了点故障
When this recording was uploaded to my data stream, it created a conflict in my programming.
我被创造出来服务保护伞公司 但是我也是珍视人类生命的
I was created to serve the Umbrella Corporation but I was also programmed to value human life.
艾萨克斯博士允许了病毒泄露  他谋杀了70亿人
Dr. Isaacs allowed the virus to escape. He murdered over 7 billion people.
我的系统不允许我伤害任何一个保护伞公司的员工
My programming will not allow me to harm an employee of the Umbrella Corporation.
我无力阻止艾萨克斯博士 但你却可以
I am powerless to stop Dr. Isaacs but you are not.
在37分钟后 人类最后的定居点将会狗带 无人能够生还
In 37 minutes, the last of the human settlements will fall. There will be no survivors.
在这发生之前你必须释放病毒抗体 否则保护伞公司就赢了
It's imperative that you release the anti virus before this occurs or Umbrella will have won.
还有最后一件事 你面前有一个耳机 戴上它
There's one last thing, there's an earpiece in front of you. Put it in.
我无法亲自伤害保护伞公司的员工 但我要告诉你 保护伞公司在浣熊市有个线人
I cannot do my actions: harm an employee of the Umbrella Corporation but I can tell you that Umbrella had an informant in Raccoon City.
而且这个人很有可能就在你的队伍里
It is highly likely that this person is now here with you.
时间不多了 爱丽丝 你得抓紧
Time is running out Alice. You have to hurry.
很高兴见到你 艾萨克斯博士
Glad to see you Dr. Isaacs.
我们觉得上次攻击之后 无人存活
We didn't think there are any survivors after the last attack.
水
Water.
是的 先生  当然
Yes sir. Of course.
给艾萨克斯博士倒点水
Get Dr. Isaacs some water.
重新开始浣熊市的进程
Then resume course for Raccoon City.
她不在那儿
She's not there.
她去了深井 我们得跟着她
She went to the pit, we have to follow.
我们得去深井
We have to go to the pit.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是哪
What is this place?
这是蜂巢的一个进风口  来吧
It's an air intake for the Hive. Come on.
别啊  真的要去
No. Really?
解除警报
All clear!
快点  电力马上要恢复了
Hurry up! The powers coming back on.
快啊  咱们走
Hurry! Let's go!
快来
Come on!
有人在监视咱们
Someone's watching us.
把涡轮向反方向旋转
Reverse polarity of the turbine.
涡轮片正在向反方向旋转
The plates are going the other way.
我们得离开这儿
We have to get out of here.
涡轮片正向后吸着空气
The plates are sucking the air backwards.
快点
Come on!
这边
This way.
我们得快
We have to hurry.
等等
Wait!
咱们走
Let's go.
莱瑟尔
Razor?
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah
咱们走
Let's go.
嗨
Hey!
这他妈是什么
What the hell is that?
生化武器 这是个人类
Bioweapon. This one's human.
你看见克莱尔了吗
Have you seen Claire?
没有
No.
莱瑟尔呢
Razor?
他没有挺过来
He didn't make it.
快点 我们得抓紧了
Come on. We have to hurry.
照这样下去 她7分钟之后就能到达这了
If the target continues on her present course, she'll be here in 7 minutes.
把他们唤醒
Wake them.
除非有极度紧急的情况 否则我不会接受这样的指令
My instructions aren't to do so. Only in the greatest of emergencies.
把他们唤醒
Wake them now.
这是什么
What is it?
我们得离开这儿
We have to get out of here.
这儿
Here.
我们去切断电源
We're stopping power.
快没时间了
Time's running out.
下一步去哪
Where to next?
蜂巢的最后一层就在我们脚下
The final level of the Hive's below us.
我们要怎么去
How do we get down there?
就像这样
Like so.
他们是什么
What are they?
低温储存
Cyrogenic storage.
这里肯定有上千个
Must be thousands of em.
保护伞最高指挥部
The Umbrella high command.
安全地等待着世界末日的结束
Waiting out the apocalypse in safety.
专为有权的有钱人打造的诺亚方舟
Noah's ark for the rich and powerful.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
帮我一把
Give me a hand.
搞定了吗
Is it done?
净化过程完成了吗
The cleansing process is complete?
没有
No.
那我为什么醒了
Then why am I awake?
我们遇到了一个问题
We had a problem.
我试着
I tried...
省省吧
Save your breath.
我知道发生了什么
I know exactly what's happening.
我们被背叛了
We've been betrayed.
对啊
That's right!
这里
Over here!
来啊 就是这儿  跟我来
Come on...that's it. Follow me.
这不是那个浪子回头的女儿吗
Or is it the prodigal daughter?
咱们走
Let's go.
这不是悔悟回家的女儿吗
Or is it the prodigal daughter?
坏苗子回来了
The bad seed returns.
这不是悔悟回家的女儿吗
Or is it the prodigal daughter?
别杵在那儿 进来
Well, don't just stand there. Come in.
毕竟你只有9分钟来拯救世界
After all you have only 9 minutes to save the world.
你是真身吗
You're really him?
首先呢 我需要你放下武器
First things first. I'm gonna need you to place your weapons on the floor.
我凭什么听你的
Why would I wanna do that?
这就是你想要的 不是吗
This is what you're after, yes?
病毒抗体 这一切的解药
The anti virus. The cure to all this.
可是解药只有一瓶哦
Well, there's only one vial.
况且我们在地下半英里的一个封闭设施里
And we're half a mile down underground in a sealed facility.
我摔了它 病毒抗体和你无望的梦想 会灰飞烟灭得更早哟
I drop it here and the anti virus goes nowhere and your hopeless dreams will die sooner rather than later.
乖宝宝
Good girl.
你还没放下枪
You're still armed.
没错
Yes, I am.
克莱尔得多么失望
Claire would be so disappointed.
几分钟后 克莱尔会和其他你认识的人一样死翘翘
A few minutes, Claire would be dead along with everybody else you know.
真棒
That's sweet.
抱歉 我的甜心
Sorry, my love.
离武器和引爆器远点
Move away from the weapon and the detonator.
她把爆炸物放在最高指挥部的低温管处 我会解除它们
She place explosives in the high command cryo tubes, I'll disarm them.
谢谢 道客 你做得很好
Thank you. You've done well Doc.
别挣扎了 你不会成功的
Don't bother. You don't make it.
无论是碎冰锥玻璃瓶或是钢笔
To the ice pick, to the decanter or the phantom pen.
至于你的问题 除了几个克隆体 我就是亚历山大·罗兰德·艾萨克斯博士
And in aswer to your question, yes apart from a few technological upgrades, I am Dr. Alexander Roland Isaacs.
本体
The original.
我在外面遇见的那个 他也觉得自己是本体
The one I met out there, he thought exactly the same thing.
当然 我们就是这么设计的
Of course he did, that's how they're designed.
我们一直不断努力尝试 不惧怕时间甚至死亡
We always try harder and fight longer even to the death.
只要他们觉得自己是本体
As long as they think they're the real thing.
毕竟 谁也不愿意知道自己只是一副毫无价值的仿制品 就像你一样
After all, who wants to know they're just a poor imitation of a worthless copy. Which brings us to you.
不
No.
得了 你不会以为自己是本体吧
Oh come on, you thought you were the original?
多美妙啊
How delicious.
不 我怀疑她还是有荣誉感的
No, I'm afraid she holds that dubious honor.
艾丽西亚·马尔库斯 我老搭档詹姆士的女儿  保护伞公司的共同所有人 我身边一根痛苦的刺
Alicia Marcus, daughter of my old partner, James. Co-owner of the Umbrella Corporation and a painful thorn in my side.
一根我现在想要拔除的刺
One I now intend to remove.
没时间了爱丽丝 你必须马上杀了他
Time is running out Alice. You must kill him soon.
我也很高兴见到你 艾丽西亚
It's good to see you too Alicia.
马尔库斯为了救她发明了T-病毒 但效果并不持久 我已经为她的死等了很久
Marcus created the T-Virus to save her but the effects didn't last but I've been waiting years for her to die.
我以为我不是克隆人
I thought I'm not a clone.
真的麽
Really?
那为什么你对你的童年 你的父母会毫无记忆
Why is it you could remember nothing of your childhood. Your father? Your mother?
丧失了记忆罢了
Memory loss.
不 你没有记忆 因为你没有人生
No, you have no memory because you have no life.
我们十年前在蜂巢创造了你之前 你什么都没有
Nothing before the mansion when we created you 10 years ago.
我知道我是谁
I know who I am.
我可不这么觉得
I don't think so.
你只不过是一个断了线的木偶 四处瞎逛了一会儿就觉得自己是个真人了 可你不是
You're nothing more than a puppet whose strings were cut and then you wandered around for a little while thinking you're a real girl but you're not
你只不过是个聪明的仿制品 一个副本 比副本更麻烦
Your just a clever imitation. A facsimile. A rather troublesome one than that.
你骗我
You're lying to me.
他并没有骗你
I'm afraid he's not.
你是照着她的样子被创造出来的  就像我一样
You are created in her image. As was I.
我的长相和声音都是艾丽西亚·马库斯的父亲根据童年时期的她创造的
My likeness and voice were based on childhood recordings of Alicia Marcus made by her father.
你的基因是根据她的DNA构造的 并被调整以防止曾折磨她的儿童早衰老化症
Your genetic structure is based on her DNA, tweak to avoid the Progerio aging disease that afflicted her.
我是儿童时代的她  你则是成年的她
I'm the child she was. You are the woman she would have been.
不 你比我要好太多 是我任由自己变弱
No, you are so much better than I ever could be. I let this happen.
我曾经很虚弱
I was weak.
你不能变成那样
You cannot afford to be.
艾丽丝 没时间了
Time is running out Alice.
啊 真感人
Ahh, that's touching.
婊子三人组 因仇恨团结在一起
The trinity of bitches, united in their hatred.
但这对你没什么任何好处  我总是会先你一步 你改变不了任何事 也救不了任何人
Well that wont do you any good. I'll be ahead of you in every step of the way. You change nothing. You've saved no one.
这个世界依旧会被肃清 保护伞公司会是最终的赢家
The world will still be cleansed and the Umbrella Corporation will triumph.
唯一不同的是 我再也不用听你那些正义的牢骚了
The only difference is, I no longer have to listen to your self righteous whining.
当你将文件上传到红后的数据库里时 你就已经背叛了公司
When you uploaded that file to the Red Queen's data stream, you turned against the corporation.
当董事会剩下的人醒了 你就会被换下
When the rest of the board awake, you will be replaced.
然后我将全权接管
And I will assume complete control.
我仍然有公司百分之五十的股份
I still own 50 percent of this company.
你又准备拿它做什么呢
And what do you intend to do with that?
你只是公司的共有者
You are co-owner of this corporation.
而威斯克呢  威斯克只是个雇员
But Wesker? Wesker is still an employee.
我不用听从你的命令 我只忠于他
I don't have to take your orders, my loyalties are with him.
我知道 阿尔伯特·威斯克 你被炒了
I know. Albert Wesker, you're fired.
你怎么知道是我做的
How did you know it was me?
因为你还活着
You're still alive.
拜托 我当时没有任何选择  是他们逼我干的
Hey, please. It wasn't like I have any choice. They made me do it.
别慌  我不会杀你的
Don't worry. I'm not gonna kill you.
克莱尔 是我啊
Claire, it's me.
对不起
Sorry.
求你
Please.
亲爱的
My love.
别别别
No no no.
如果你一直不按下这个扣板 你就一直纵容保护伞公司的梦想不死
If you keep this trigger unpressed, you keep Umbrella's dreams alive.
早知当初我应该在华盛顿杀了你
I should have killed you in Washington.
是啊
Yeah.
他只需要再背叛你几分钟
He only has to deviate you for another few minutes.
人类最后的村落就会消失了
And the last remaining human outposts will fall.
我们需要拦住他 然后以最快的方式到达地球表面
We need an intercept path and a fastest way to the surface.
已经完成了
Already done.
如果你释放了病毒抗体 它就会杀死所有被T病毒感染的有机体  你知道这对你而言意味着什么吧
If you release the anti virus, it will kill all organisms infected with the T-Virus. You know what that means don't you? For you?
我知道
I know.
艾丽丝 你不能这么做
Alice, you can't.
我别无选择
I don't have a choice.
一定还有其他的解决办法
There has to be another way.
你知道这是唯一的办法
You know there isn't.
只剩四分钟零三十三秒 你得抓紧了
4 minutes and 33 seconds left, you have to hurry.
帮帮我
Help me.
你不需要帮助 威斯克
You don't need help Wesker.
你快死了  习惯就好
You're dying. Just get on with it.
我是亚历山大·罗兰德·艾萨克斯博士  启动DNA和声纹身份验证
This is Dr. Alexander Roland Isaacs. Confirm DNA scan and voice print identification.
身份已确认
Identity confirmed.
安全系统启动 取消4365号的控制权
Confirm security override 4365.
已取消
Override confirmed.
现在自动离线 然后将一切功能交予我单独控制
Well now take yourself offline and place all functions under my sole control.
遵命 正在关机
As you wish, shutting down now.
艾萨克斯博士 你和保护伞公司的高层
Dr. Isaacs, you and the Umbrella high command.
怎样
Yes?
你们都会死在下面
You're all going to die down here.
你的小伙伴也帮不了你了
Your little friend won't be able to help you now.
你逃不掉了
You can't run anymore.
我并没有逃
I wasn't running.
你就这点本事了吗
Is that all you got?
如果就这点本事 我就得杀了你
Cause if it is, I'm gonna have to kill you.
我们已经玩得够久了 你和我
We've played a long game you and I.
但现在一切都结束了
But now it's over.
是啊
Yes.
是的
Yes it is.
我创造了你
I made you.
是的
Yeah.
你犯了个大错
Big mistake.
克莱尔
Claire.
快走 趁着还有时间
Go! While there's still time.
走  我就跟在你的后面
Go, I'll be right behind you.
你没时间了
Your time's up.
艾丽丝  我带他们来了
Alice  I've brought them here.
我为你把他们带来了
I've brought them for you.
你是谁
What the hell are you?
我是你啊 傻瓜
I'm you, you idiot.
不 不
No. No.
不 这不可能
No, that's not possible.
我是真的你
The real you.
不可能
No.
骗子  讨厌的家伙
Liar! Abomination!
肮脏的家伙
Filthy!
我才是我  他不是我
I'm me. He's not me.
你做到了 艾丽丝 艾丽丝
You did it Alice. Alice.
你做到了
You did it!
为什么我还活着
Why am I still alive?
我不知道
I don't know.
发生了什么
What happened?
艾萨克斯死后 我便可以重新自动上线 阻止对剩下人类安置点的攻击
When Isaacs died, I could bring myself back online and stop the attacks on the remaining human settlements.
是你拯救了他们
You saved them.
为什么我还活着
Why am I still alive?
病毒抗体只摧毁了你体内的T病毒  它并没有伤害你体内健康的细胞
The anti virus only destroyed the T-Virus within your body. It didn't harm the healthy cells.
你现在已经不受病毒感染了
You are now free of infection.
你说我会死掉 你和艾丽西亚都这样说 你们骗了我
You thought I would die, you and Alicia. You lied to me.
我们得知道你是否愿意做出牺牲 舍弃自己的生命去拯救大家
We had to know if you are willing to make the sacrifice. To give up your life for others.
保护伞公司里没有第二个人会这样做了
This was something no one at Umbrella would have done.
艾丽西亚·马库斯是对的
Alicia Marcus was right about you.
你是他们中最棒的
You were better than all of them.
我也曾是其中一员 我是被保护伞公司创造的
I was one of them. I was created by Umbrella.
我只是他们的一个工具
Just an instrument for them.
不 你远超出了他们的预料
No, you became something more than they could ever have anticipated.
克隆人变得比人类更人类
The clone became more human than they ever could be.
你只剩一步未迈出了
And you have one more step to make.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
艾丽西亚死前为你上传了她的记忆
Before she died, Alicia uploaded her memories for you.
记忆里是你从未有过的童年
The childhood you never had.
正好可以和你拥有 而她无法经历的成年记忆相结合
Combined with the woman she could never become.
T病毒在地球上
When the T-Virus spread across the earth.
以喷气客机为载体
It did so at the speed of the modern world.
很快便散播开了
Carried by jet liners across the globe.
病毒抗体在空中 随风传播
The anti virus is airborne, spread by the winds.
也许要花上几年它才能散播到地球的每个角落
It could take years for it to reach every corner of the earth.
不到那时 我的工作就不会结束
Until then, my work here is not done.
我的名字叫艾丽丝
My name is Alice.
你好 爱丽丝
西
浣熊市
使用者未经授权
保护伞之家
欢迎来到浣熊市
伸冤在我 我必报应
保护性搏斗软件
生命维持：危急
系统故障
生命维持：0%
{\bord0\shad0\fscx0\fsp2\t(22,300,1,\fscx90)\t(1000,1100,1,\fry90)\c&H7F7A6D&\pos(649,46)}生化危机6
EF字幕组
翻译 传承者 橙子 伊塔 Riki 珍珠草
校对 鼠大
监制 卫溪
特效 豆包